Paola Valdivia

Research engineer Télécom Paris

OVERVIEW

I am a researcher in the field of visual analytics, a practice that brings together data analysis, information visualization, HCI methods, and software development. My research focuses on network visual analysis, leveraging mathematical network models, and information visualization to create new analysis methods for large datasets, where the interconnection of their pieces can lead to significant insights. These projects led to several internationally peer-reviewed publications at IEEE VIS, Eurovis, and TVCG.

Professional experience

Research Engineer

Peru Credit Bank (BCP)

B.S. Informatics Engineering (Computer Science)

o Télécom Paris

Postdoctoral Researcher France Inria Saclay Jun 2018 - May 2020 Research Consultant Brazil Visibilia Dec 2018 - Jul 2019 Research internship France Inria Saclay Aug 2016 - Jul 2017 Research internship USA New York University Nov 2015 Software Developer Peru

EDUCATION

University of São Paulo Brazil ° Ph.D. Computer Science Dec 2013 - May 2018 University of São Paulo o M.Sc. Computer Science Aug 2011 - Nov 2013 San Pablo Catholic University Peru

EXPERTISE

visual analytics network visualization data science graph signal processing

> paola.valdivia@inria.fr +33 06 25938033

paolavaldivia.github.io

France

Jun 2020 - present

Aug 2010 - Jul 2011

2005 - 2010



paolavaldivia 🖸



paolavaldivia in

FOREIGN LANGUAGES

english fluent french professional spanish native portuguese fluent

REFERENCES

Dr. Jean Daniel Fekete AVIZ Team Leader Inria Saclay lean-Daniel.Fekete@inria.fr +55163373-9697

Dr. Luis Gustavo Nonato Full Professor University of Sao Paulo gnonato@icmc.usp.br +55(16)3373-9697

> Dr. Catherine Plaisant Senior Research Scientist University of Maryland plaisant@cs.umd.edu +1 (301) 405-2768

- Pister, A., Buono, P., Fekete, J. D., Plaisant, C., and **Valdivia**, **P.** (2020). *Analyzing Dynamic Hypergraphs with Parallel Aggregated Ordered Hypergraph Visualization*. to appear in IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics.
- Valdivia, P., Buono, P., Plaisant C., Dufournaud N. and Fekete, J.-D. (2020). *Integrating Prior Knowledge in Mixed Initiative Social Network Clustering*. To appear in IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics.
- Ferreira, V., Valejo, A., **Valdivia, P.** and Valverde-Rebaza, J. (2019) *Exploiting Geographical Data to improve Recommender Systems for Business Opportunities in Urban Areas*. To appear in Proceedings of BRACIS 2019.
- o Dias, M.D, **Valdivia, P.**, Petronetto, F., Nonato, L. G. (2018). *Graph Spectral Filtering for Network Simplification*. In Graphics, Patterns and Images (SIBGRAPI), 2018 31st SIBGRAPI-Conference. IEEE.
- Col, A. D., Valdivia, P., Petronetto, F., Dias, F., Silva, C. T., and Nonato, L. G. (2017). Wavelet-based visual analysis of dynamic networks. IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics.
- Col, A. D., Valdivia, P., Petronetto, F., Dias, F., Silva, C. T., and Nonato, L. G. (2017). Wavelet-based visual analysis for data exploration. Computing in Science Engineering.
- Dias, F., Mansour, M. R., **Valdivia, P.**, Cousty, J., and Najman, L. (2017). *Watersheds on Hypergraphs for Data Clustering*. In International Symposium on Mathematical Morphology and Its Applications to Signal and Image Processing. Springer, Cham.
- Valdivia, P., Dias, F., Petronetto, F., Silva, C. T., and Nonato, L. G. (2015). Wavelet-based visualization of time-varying data on graphs. In Visual Analytics Science and Technology (VAST), 2015 IEEE Conference.
- Søren Knudsen, Jan Aerts, Daniel Archambault, Remco Chang, Jean-Daniel Fekete, Valdivia, P. et al. (2019) Unifying the framework of Multi-Layer Network and Visual Analytics. Visual Analytics of Multilayer Networks Across Disciplines, Dagstuhl Reports.
- Valdivia, P., Cedrim, D., Petronetto, F., Paiva, A., and Nonato, L. G. (2013). Normal Correction towards Smoothing Point-Based Surfaces. In Graphics, Patterns and Images (SIBGRAPI), 2013 26th SIBGRAPI-Conference. IEEE.

SHORT PAPERS

• **Valdivia, P.**, Buono, P., Plaisant C., Dufournaud N. and Fekete, J.-D. (2018). *Using Dynamic Hypergraphs to Reveal the Evolution of the Business Network of a 17th Century French Woman Merchant*. VIS 2018-3rd Workshop on Visualization for the Digital Humanities.

POSTERS

- **Valdivia, P.**, Buono, P., and Fekete, J.-D. (2017). *Hypenet: Visualizing Dynamic Hypergraphs*. In Puig, A. P. and Isenberg, T., editors, EuroVis 2017 Posters. The Eurographics Association.
- Dimara, E., **Valdivia, P.**, and Kinkeldey, C. (2017). *DcPAIRS: A Pairs Plot Based Decision Support System*. In Puig, A. P. and Isenberg, T., editors, EuroVis 2017 Posters. The Eurographics Association.

SOFTWARE PROTOTYPES AND CONTRIBUTIONS

- **PK-clustering**. Prototype for creating meaningful clusters in social networks. Implemented in Dart using web canvas and a Flask server. http://paovis.ddns.net/paoh.html
- Paohvis. Prototype for visualizing dynamic multi-entity relationships.
 Implemented in Dart using web canvas. http://www.aviz.fr/paohvis/
- **Waviz**. Prototype for analyzing spatio-temporal data based on graph signal porcessing. Implemented in JavaScript using D3. https://paolavaldivia.github.io/waviz/
- **Siion**. Prototype for showing the best potential regions for opening a business in the city of São Paulo. Implemented in Javascript using React and Mapbox http://siion.visibilia.net.br
- **Dynamic Network Explorer**. Prototype for analyzing dynamic networks based on graph signal porcessing. Implemented in JavaScript using the framework AngularJS and D3. https://paolavaldivia.github.io/dynnet_wavelet/
- Networkcube. Reimplemented the matrix visualization for exploring networks. Implemented in Typescript using WebGL and D3. http://networkcube.net/